# Prakhar Ganesh

COMPUTER SCIENCE · PHD STUDENT

McGill University | Quebec Al Institute (Mila)

Research Interests: I am interested in the challenges that arise in machine learning when moving from the sandbox to the real world, primarily at the intersection of various pillars in trustworthy machine learning, including fairness, privacy, adversarial robustness, model compression, etc., focusing on uncovering the learning dynamics of neural networks.

### **Education**

### McGill University | Quebec AI Institute (Mila)

PHD COMPUTER SCIENCE (THESIS) | ADVISOR: PROF GOLNOOSH FARNADI

Jan 2024 - Present

#### **National University of Singapore (NUS)**

MASTER OF COMPUTING (AI SPECIALISATION) | ADVISOR: PROF REZA SHOKRI

Aug 2021 - Mar 2023

#### Indian Institute of Technology Delhi (IITD)

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Aug 2015 - May 2019

## **Work Experience**

NATIONAL UNIVERSITY OF SINGAPORE (NUS) | RESEARCH INTERN ALVISUAL | AI ENGINEER (INTERN)

Jan 2023 - Apr 2023 Jan 2022 - Mar 2022

ADVANCED DIGITAL SCIENCES CENTER (ADSC) | RESEARCH ENGINEER

Jun 2019 - July 2021

WEALTHNET ADVISORS | ANALYST (INTERN)

Jan 2019 - May 2019 May 2018 - July 2018

## **Publications**

KRIDA.AI | ENGINEER (INTERN)

#### Towards More Realistic Extraction Attacks: An Adversarial Perspective

[NON-ARCHIVAL] WORKSHOP ON PRIVACY IN NATURAL LANGUAGE PROCESSING, 2024

Yash More, Prakhar Ganesh, Golnoosh Farnadi

### An Empirical Investigation into Benchmarking Model Multiplicity for Trustworthy Machine Learning

IEEE/CVF WINTER CONFERENCE ON APPLICATIONS OF COMPUTER VISION (WACV), 2024

**Prakhar Ganesh** 

#### On The Impact of Machine Learning Randomness on Group Fairness

[BEST PAPER AWARD] ACM CONFERENCE ON FAIRNESS, ACCOUNTABILITY AND TRANSPARENCY (FACCT), 2023

Prakhar Ganesh, Hongyan Chang, Martin Strobel, Reza Shokri

#### YOLO-ReT: Towards High Accuracy Real-time Object Detection on Edge GPUs

IEEE/CVF WINTER CONFERENCE ON APPLICATIONS OF COMPUTER VISION (WACV), 2022

Prakhar Ganesh, Yao Chen, Yin Yang, Deming Chen, Marianne Winslett

#### HiKonv: High Throughput Quantized Convolution With Novel Bit-wise Management and Computation

ASIA AND SOUTH PACIFIC DESIGN AUTOMATION CONFERENCE (ASP-DAC), 2022

Yao Chen, Xinheng Liu, Prakhar Ganesh, Junhao Pan, Jinjun Xiong, Deming Chen

#### Compressing Large-Scale Transformer-Based Models: A Case Study on BERT

TRANSACTIONS OF THE ASSOCIATION FOR COMPUTATIONAL LINGUISTICS (TACL), 2021

Prakhar Ganesh, Yao Chen, Xin Lou, Mohd. Ali Khan, Yin Yang, Hassan Sajjad, Preslav Nakov, Deming Chen, Marianne Winslett

#### Learning-based Detection and Characterization of Time Delay Attack in Cyber-Physical Systems

IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON SMART GRID (TSG), 2021

Prakhar Ganesh, Xin Lou, Yao Chen, Rui Tan, David K.Y. Yau, Deming Chen, Marianne Winslett

#### Assessing and Mitigating the Impact of Time Delay Attack: Case Studies for Power Grid Controls

IEEE JOURNAL ON SELECTED AREAS IN COMMUNICATIONS (JSAC), 2020

Xin Lou, Cuong Tran, Rui Tan, David K.Y. Yau, Zbigniew T. Kalbarczyk, Ambarish Kumar Banerjee, Prakhar Ganesh

# **Preprints/Manuscripts**

#### The Data Minimization Principle in Machine Learning

ARXIV PREPRINT ARXIV:2405.19471

Prakhar Ganesh, Cuong Tran, Reza Shokri, Ferdinando Fioretto

#### Free Lunch for Co-Saliency Detection: Context Adjustment

ARXIV PREPRINT ARXIV:2108.02093

Lingdong Kong, Prakhar Ganesh, Tan Wang, Junhao Liu, Le Zhang, Yao Chen

#### Restructuring Conversations using Discourse Relations for Zero-shot Abstractive Dialogue Summarization

ARXIV PREPRINT ARXIV:1902.01615

Prakhar Ganesh, Saket Dingliwal

#### **VLSTM: Very Long Short-Term Memory Networks for High-Frequency Trading**

ARXIV PREPRINT ARXIV:1809.01506

Prakhar Ganesh, Puneet Rakheja

#### Nucl2Vec: Local alignment of DNA sequences using Distributed Vector Representation

BIORXIV PREPRINT DOI:10.1101/401851

Prakhar Ganesh, Gaurav Gupta, Shubhi Saini, Kolin Paul

## **Invited Talks**

FATE Reading Group, Quebec AI Institute (Mila), The Cost of Arbitrariness for Individuals: Examining the

Legal and Technical Challenges of Model Multiplicity

- Jan 2024 Saarland University, On The Impact of Machine Learning Randomness on Model Fairness
- May 2023 Quebec Al Institute (Mila), On The Impact of Machine Learning Randomness on Model Fairness

## Awards and Scholarships

- 2024 **Travel Grant**, ACM Conference on Fairness, Accountability and Transparency (FAccT)
- 2024 **Doctoral Research Scholarship**, Fonds de recherche du Québec Nature et Technologies (FRQNT)
- 2024 Graduate Research Enhancement And Travel (GREAT) Award, McGill University
- 2024 Excellence Scholarship EDI in Research Category, Mila EDI Scholarship Program
- 2024 Graduate Excellence Award, McGill University
- 2023 **Graduate Scholarship**, Prof. Golnoosh Farnadi, Quebec Al Institute (Mila)
- 2023 Best Paper Award, ACM Conference on Fairness, Accountability and Transparency (FAccT)
- 2023 Travel Grant, ACM Conference on Fairness, Accountability and Transparency (FAccT)
- 2022 Winner, 8-Bit Bias Bounty Competition Supervised Learning Track
- 2021 **Top 3 Teams**, ASP-DAC System Design Contest

## **Professional and Volunteer Service**

- 2024 **Peer Reviewer,** ACL Rolling Review (ARR), July Cycle
- 2024 **Peer Reviewer**, Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS)
- 2024 Peer Reviewer, Widening Natural Language Processing Workshop (WiNLP), EMNLP
- 2024 Volunteer, ACM Conference on Fairness, Accountability and Transparency (FAccT)
- 2024 **Peer Reviewer**, Responsible Generative AI Workshop, CVPR
- 2024 Ethics Reviewer, ACL Rolling Review (ARR), Feb Cycle
- 2024 **Peer Reviewer**, ACL Rolling Review (ARR), Feb Cycle
- 2024 **Program Committee (PC) Member**, ACM Conference on Fairness, Accountability and Transparency (FAccT)
- 2024 **Peer Reviewer**, Winter Conference on Application of Computer Vision (WACV)
- 2023 **Peer Reviewer**, Algorithmic Fairness through the lens of Time (AFT) Workshop, NeurIPS
- 2023 **Ethics Reviewer**, Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS)
- 2023 **Peer Reviewer**, Al Communications
- 2022 **Peer Reviewer**, Winter Conference on Application of Computer Vision (WACV)
- 2021 **Peer Reviewer**, AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI)
- 2021 Peer Reviewer, Winter Conference on Application of Computer Vision (WACV)
- 2020 **Peer Reviewer**, Computer Speech and Language
- 2020 **Peer Reviewer**, Signal, Image and Video Processing

# Teaching/Mentorship Experience

- 2024 **Teaching Assistant**, Fall-COMP-370: Introduction to Data Science, McGill University
- 2024 **Instructor**, Indigenous Pathfinders in Al
- 2024 **Teaching Assistant**, Al4Good Lab: Summer ML Bootcamp
- 2024 **Coding Mentor**, Girls Who Code Hackathon
- 2024 **Teaching Assistant**, Winter-COMP-553: Algorithmic Game Theory, McGill University